# Senior Frontend Developer: Alessio Prestileo

**Date of birth:** 1986-07-20 **E-mail:** alessioprestileo@gmail.com

Nationality: Italy LinkedIn: https://no.linkedin.com/in/alessioprestileoalep

Mobile: +1 458 600 4103 GitHub: https://github.com/alessioprestileo

Address: 3752 SW Tommy Armour Lane, Redmond, OR 97756, United States



# **Summary**

Highly experienced Senior Frontend Developer with a strong background in software architecture and engineering. Proven track record of success in developing and maintaining web and mobile applications using a variety of languages and frameworks. Excellent problem-solving skills, attention to detail, and ability to mentor and review code for less experienced developers.

Here's what my team lead has to say about me:

- "I know I can give you just about any task, and you will find a great solution to it."
- "You have been vital to the team's success."
- "Your bandwidth is impressive."

#### **Skills**

- Extensive knowledge of TypeScript and very strong interest in static typing.
- Extensive knowledge of JavaScript, HTML, CSS.
- Solid experience in reviewing code and tutoring less experienced developers.
- Strong focus on writing clean, readable and maintainable code.
- Productive in any JavaScript/TypeScript framework.
- Solid understanding of software architecture principles and design patterns.

# **Work Experience**

# Senior Frontend Developer at Forsta AS (formerly Confirmit AS)

Oslo, Norway and remote, US

Jun 2020 - Present

- Acted as main contact for any TypeScript-related questions within the company.
- Improved type safety on a 500k lines TypeScript codebase through large-scale refactorings, practically eliminating runtime errors.
- Contributed to new features by writing implementation, unit tests and e2e tests.
- Spent ~20% of working time reviewing pull requests from other developers.
- Solved a variety of urgent bugs reported by users, as well as well known problems caused by poor architecture.
- Significantly improved deployment pipeline built with TeamCity (increased automation, reduced build time).
- Collaborated with UI/UX experts to enhance user experience and contributed to development and maintenance of a company-wide design system.
- Played a key role in technical interviews for hiring of new frontend developers (~50 candidates assessed in 2022, 12 candidates hired).
- Significantly improved developer experience by developing coding conventions and internal tooling.
- Contributed to the development and maintenance of an internal design system counting ~50 UI components.
- Assumed leadership in overseeing and delivering impactful, large-scale projects, collaborating with crossfunctional teams of developers spanning diverse areas of expertise.

#### System Developer at Zirius AS

Oslo, Norway

Jun 2018 - May 2020

- Developed an ERP web application and an expense claim mobile app using React, React-Native and TypeScript.
- Created and maintained npm packages for internal use and developed coding conventions.
- Created a deployment pipeline using Jenkins.
- Implemented OAuth 2.0 authentication for web and mobile clients and contributed to definition of backend APIs using Swagger.
- Assumed the role of frontend lead, mentoring and performing code reviews for less experienced developers.
- Performed interviews, created tests and home assignments to assess new frontend developers.

#### System Developer at Acando AS (now CGI)

Oslo, Norway

Feb 2018 - May 2018

- Built the frontend of a web application for Boneprox, using React, Redux, and Flow.

# System Developer at 07 Media AS

Oslo, Norway

Jan 2017 - Jan 2018

- Developed and maintained websites using Drupal and Wordpress on the backend, Angular and Vue on the frontend.
- Key contributor to the development and maintenance speiding.no and tradisjonsmat.no

# Structural Engineer at DNV

Oslo, Norway

Sep 2011 - Jan 2016

- Performed advanced analysis (non-linear FE analysis) to assess the ultimate strength of marine structures.
- Developed customized features for engineering applications using Python and C++.

# Independent Study

Jan 2016 - Present

- In-depth study of strongly typed functional languages: Haskell, PureScript and Elm.
- Completed "Master Class in Software Architecture" course taught by "Uncle Bob" Martin.
- Explored the fundamentals of 3D graphics in OpenGL.
- Studied of C and C++ with advanced use of pointers, templates and polymorphism.

#### **Education**

Master's degree: Naval Architecture and Marine Engineering

Mar 2011

University of Genova, Italy

Bachelor's degree: Naval Architecture and Marine Engineering

Oct 2008

University of Genova, Italy

# Language Skills

Native	Proficient	Beginner
Italian	English, Norwegian, Portuguese, Spanish	French